# 四伯爷这是什么刀
What kind of knife is it, uncle?
# 这是杀猪儿做烫皮的刨子
This is a plane for removing pig hair, after butchering and scalding its skin
# 你磨那么快咋子安
Why did you make it so sharp?
# 不磨快就刨不动
It has to be sharp enough to plane
# 要磨一下不是那个刨子刨不动
It must be sharpened. Or it can't plane
# 这个也是吗
Is this also a plane?
# 这个也是
Yes
# 好我去烧水
OK. I'll boil some water
# 要得好
Sure
# 好得
Good
# 这个野猪的毛
The hair of this wild pig...
# 跟家猪的不一样
is different from domestic pigs
# 嗯跟家猪不一样
Yeah, different from domestic pigs
# 没有我想象中那么难刮
It's not as hard as I thought to remove the hair
# 但是也不是那么好刮
But it's not quite easy anyways
# 毛比较硬还会扎手
The hair is pretty hard. And it pricks my hands
# 那个毛去开咋子是白色的呢
Why is it white after removing the hair?
# 怎么不是呢
Why not?
# 这把刀儿好快
This knife is so sharp
# 肯定很快啊
Sharp for sure
# 咦这个猪肝才安逸
Wow this liver is nice
# 嗯
Yeah
# 炒得到一盘子不
Can we make a full dish from it?
# 好大哟
It's so big
# 好可以了
Yeah, good
# 经过上次我们烤那个羊
After grilling that goat last time
# 现在我研究了一点新花样出来
now I've discovered some new tactics
# 就是改进一下这个技术
I mean, there are some technical improvements
# 就是腌的时候我切点柠檬
So I'm slicing some lemons for the marination
# 切点柠檬水然后加一点那个料酒
Make some lemon juice, and add some cooking wine
# 一起放到这里面待会用来直接喷
Put them in the sprayer so that we can just spray it (on the meat) later
# 防止那个猪肉温度过高
To prevent overheating the pork
# 防止它糊
Or it could be scorched
# 既可以去腥又可以降温
It's for both odor removal and temperature control
# 切开
Slice it open
# 这个柠檬去腥效果比较好
Lemons are quite effective for odor removal
# 这个是柠檬汁
This is the lemon juice
# 我自己配的料酒
Cooking wine that I made by myself
# 刚刚好
Just right
# 嗯可以
Hmm, good
# 然后这个给它切碎
These will be minced
# 拿来跟那个姜葱一起切碎了
minced together with ginger and green onions
# 放盐来抹在那个猪上面
And then rub it on the pork, together with salt
# 腌味腌底味
Marination. For a base flavor
# 再放点盐
Add a bit salt
# 嗯可以有点咸
Hmm, good. A little salty
# 加点水
Add some water
# 差不多
Looks good
# 腌猪肉了先
Let's marinate the pork
# 我们先用这个刚刚调的酱料涂一下
Let's rub it with the seasoning sauce that we just made
# 腌一下给它入一下味
Marinate it. Let the flavor penetrate
# 好腌在这里
Alright. Leave it here for marination
# 一会就可以烤啦
We can start grilling in a bit
# 这个位置吧
This position, right?
# 四点钟了可以生碳烤起了
It's 4 o'clock now. We can light the char and grill
# 可以升堂了
We can light ???
# 嗯升堂 生炭
???
# 这个猪小了下次杀个大点的猪儿来吃
This pig is too small. Let's get a bigger one next time
# 那个部位咋个炒起好吃那个部位的肉咋个炒起好吃
Which part should be cooked in what way
# 对
Right
# 对我伯爷三十多年的那个经验
According to my uncle's experience for more than 30 years
# 可以告诉你们这个猪怎么样去分解
He can tell you how to divide a pig
# 哪一个部位该怎么吃
and how to cook each cut
# 这个是我伯爷的专业
That's the area uncle is professional in
# 这一块的脖子肉比较厚所以要多一些碳
The neck meat is thicker. So there's more charcoal here
# 然后后面的话要矮一些
And there's less for the rear part
# 假如我们把这个火离得太近了
If we put it too close to the fire
# 表面烤焦了中间还没熟
the outside will be burned while the inside is still raw
# 因为这个肉最厚的地方 有这么厚
as the thickest part of the meat is this thick
# 待会烤熟了再用把刀把它划开
After it's cooked, we can slice it open with a knife
# 划开了再喷上我们那个姜姜葱还有那个料酒
Slice it, and then spray the ginger, green onion, and cooking wine
# 现在我们这个碳已经起上来了但是火焰还没起来
Now we've already lit the charcoal, but the heat hasn't come out yet
# 现在这个天快五点钟了
Now it's almost 5 o'clock
# 可能我们吃到这个烤猪的时候都是晚上天黑去了
It will be probably dark when we can start eating
# 正好嘛
Actually
# 天黑的时候
when it becomes dark
# 那个时候肯定肚子饿了
We must be hungry enough then
# 等这个碳起来了就很快了
It won't take long when the charcoal starts to burn
# 但是我又不想两下把它烤熟
But I don't want to cook it too fast
# 因为快速烤熟的猪肉表面是焦的里面里面还有水份
It's because, if it's quickly cooked, the skin would be burned while there's still too much moisture left inside
# 一点都不好吃 这个一点要把它烤干烤脆
which isn't tasty at all. So we must grill it to dry and crispy
# 把水份烤干一点然后时间烤长一点才对得起这个野猪肉嘛
Grill away the moisture, and grill for long enough. That's how to properly treat the meat of a wild pig
# 看到了吗 这个葱皮已经烤干了
See? The green onion is already grilled to dry
# 烤干了
It's already dry
# 说明这个火力已经起来了
Which means the heat has already come out
# 现在这个肉已经收紧了
Now the meat is already tightened
# 把它割一下稍微
Let's slice it for a bit
# 让它这个中间能够熟得更均匀一点
So that the pork can be cooked evenly
# 用刀尖慢慢的轻轻的给它划一下
Slice it tenderly and slowly with the tip of the knife
# 这个是猪的脖子的位置
This part is the neck of the pig
# 这个位置的话要划深一点
We should slice deeper here
# 因为它的肉也比较厚
as the meat is thicker here
# 给它插一下
Poke it for a bit
# 更均匀一点
to make it more even
# 下面的油滴得噼里啪啦的响
Can you hear the sound of oil dropping down?
# 听到了吗 这个下面的皮已经脆了
Can you hear it? The skin has already turned crispy
# 你看这个皮已经脆了
The skin is already crispy
# 你看这个都已经快黄了
Now this is already very golden yellow
# 现在我要搞点这个上去因为它温度有点高
Now I'll spray it, as the temperate is a bit too high
# 得给它降一下
Gotta reduce it
# 降一下温的话它就没有那么容易焦
Reduce the temperature, so that it's not too burned
# 你们吃得辣不辣
How spicy can you eat?
# 吃得辣的话多撒一点
If you can eat very spicy, I'll add more
# 终于好啦三个小时啊这个等了
Finally! Three hours of waiting
# 放上来吧
Let's put it here
# 四伯爷快来这里
Uncle, come here
# 我还有点
Here
# 你听哈看
Listen
# 哎哟那个响声还有点好唉
Aiyo, that sounds terrific
# 烤焦啊的哦嗯是
Well grilled, isn't it?
# 安逸安
Nice
# 我剁一坨给你吃
Let me slice a piece for you
# 这坨
This piece
# 这个的皮子最安逸
The skin is the best part
# 我尝一坨
Let me try it
# 咦 安逸安
Eh, nice, isn't it?
# 比上次那个烤全羊都鲜
It's even more delicious than the whole grilled goat last time
# 嗯
Hmm
# 很脆这个特别的脆
This is crispy. Very crispy
# 这个比竹鼠还要脆
Even more crispy than bamboo rat
# 安逸
Nice
# 嗯
Hmm
# 好吃
Tasty
# 我弄一坨肉给你吃
Let me cut a piece of meat for you
# 安逸
Nice
# 好吃真的好吃
Tasty. For real!
# 嗯 真的安逸
Hmm, really nice
# 四伯爷有啤酒没得哦
Do we have beer, uncle?
# 有
Yeah
# 有我们喝点啤酒嘛
Yeah, then let's have some beer?
# 好嘛好嘛我去拿一瓶来
Sure thing. Let me bring a bottle
# 好啦本期视频就到这里啦
Alright, that's all of this video
# 我们要开始吃肉喝点小啤酒
Now we'll start to eat the pork and drink some beer
# 拜拜
Bye bye